Mohammad Vatandoost Silab

Embedded Software Engineer

Cell: +98-937-1869568 Email: mohamadvatandoost512@gmail.com

Date of birth: 19/08/1995

Summary

I have more than 6 years experience in Embedded, Desktop and Back-End Software development for small and medium Enterprises. I participate in all phases of the software development life cycle. I mainly work with C/C++, Qt framework, Golang and Python. The most of my working experience is in a team, I enjoy to help my team to solve problems.

Experience

Software Engineer

Aug 2020 - present

Fanap-infra.ir

Fannap-infra is Developing multiple Software projects. I am working in Behnama projects team. Behnama is a video surveillance software.

Behnama is built on microservice architecture, it contains RTSP client, recording, web-app, webrtc, API, analyzer, Kafka, ONVIF, PostgressDB and influxDB services.

- Writing a WebRTC player backend for playing live and records. It receives commands and sends records list and metadata by WebRTC data channel Go
- Using GRPC for communication between microservices Go, C++ and Python
- Receiving RTSP(IP Camera stream) by ffmpeg library C/C++
- Using Kafka for streaming media and Metadata packets Go, C++ and Python
- Creating recording file structure for minimizing head movement of HDD Go
- Adding motion detection (by OpenCV) to analyzer service Python
- Dockerise Stream and RTSP services

Software Engineer

3ddreams.ir

Dec 2019 – Jul 2020 (8 months)

3DDreams build the industry 3D printer Devices. I developed server and clinet software for the device. The server software is running in a raspberry pi inside the device and the client software is a cross platform app that run in a desktop computer.

- Adding unit test with gTest to client and server project C++
- Implementing UI of Client project by Qml
- Socket programming and using protobuf for messages structure C++
- Using Serial Port for Communication with actuator C++.

Embedded Software Engineer

raiwan.ir

Nov 2017 – OCT 2019 (2 years)

Raiwan works on designing and building IoT and industrial manufacturing and labratory devices.

I developed softwars for industrial devices. I designed and implemented Algorithms for different use cases, such as: Oil industry, IoT, Polymer industry and civil industry.

- Receiving data from Socket at rate 96 MBit, then simultaneously Decode,
 Decrypt(Cryptopp library) and Mux(ffmpeg library) H.264 and audio(PCM to AAC) frames C/C++
- Writing a Linux USB Driver C
- Working with RS485 mode bus protocol in industrial devices C++
- Developing Android app that connect to modules by BLE and OTG, It receives files and send user commands Java

FreeLancer

Feb 2016 – Sep 2017 (1 year and 8 months)

I worked with multiple start ups to build theirs MVP products.

- Receiving sensors data in real time from serial port and plot them by QtChart C++
- Preprocessing data by FFT and filters like Butterworth and averaging data chunk.
- Converting matlab code of constumers to C++ code.
- Using UART and I2C protocol in Orange pi and Raspberry pi.
- Designing relational data base.
- Crawling websites with Selenium Java

Student Researcher

KNTU Aras robotic Lab

Nov 2014 – Jan 2016 (1 year and 3 months)

KNTU Aras robotic Lab research on UGV and MAV. I designed and programmed robot's Embedded system.

- ARM Microcontroller(Stm32 series) and AVR programming (Used I2C, UART, SPI, PWM, USB and ADC peripherals).
- PCB Design of Embedded systems.
- Working with Different sensors and Electronics modules.

Education

- University of Tehran, MS, Computer Software Engineering, (2019 2021) (GPA: 3.5/4)
- K. N. Toosi University of Technology, BS, Electronic Engineering, (2013 2018) (GPA: 3.3/4)

AWARDS

- Aut cup 2016
 - Our Team achieved the second place in Rescue robots competition.
- IRAN Open 2015 robotic competition
 Our Team achieved the first place in diminer robots competition.
- Chess Competition
 I achieved the first place in chess competition between high schools students

Teaching

Embedded software development course in Robotic lab of K. N. Toosi University of Technology

Skills

C/C++ - Qt - Golang - Unit Testing — Message Queue(Kafka) — GRPC - Cmake - Protobuf - Linux Driver development — Embedded Systems — Python - DataBase Design — Java - Socket Programming — Onvif - MySQL, Sqlite, PostgresSQL and influxdb — PID — Docker - RS485, RS232, I2C and UART Protocols - STM32(ARM Cortex-M) - Git

Language

- Persian (Native)
- English (Full professional proficiency)
- Azerbaijani (Full professional proficiency)

Interests

- Soccer
- Tech Articles
- Movies